Colleen Thompson 1617 President Street, D2 Brooklyn, NY 11213 301.996.8406 Colleen.l.thompson@gmail.com

January 7, 2013

Tutors on Wheels 68-60 Austin Street Forest Hills, NY 11375

Greetings,

As a proponent for the holistic progress of youth, I am pleased to apply for a tutor position with Tutors on Wheels. I have five years experience teaching youth workshops within community-based organizations. I also hold a Master of Arts in Women's Health with an emphasis on education and policy directives, which strengthens my ability to assist young people to develop their full potential.

While at The Brooklyn Young Mothers' Collective, I conducted comprehensive reproductive health trainings for pregnant and parenting teens at a detention center in Staten Island. In addition, I successfully created and implemented a civic involvement initiative, built curriculum, and tutored my program members at need. Through my organizing work I routinely facilitated financial literacy, grassroots fundraising and violence prevention workshops. I currently teach creative writing and media education classes that meet the Common Core State Standards within public schools.

I am thrilled by the work your company does and I look forward to discussing the specific ways I can contribute. Please feel free to contact me at your convenience. Thank you for your time and consideration.

Sincerely,

Colleen Thompson M.A. Women's Health

Colleen Thompson

Address: 1617 President Street, D2 Brooklyn, NY 11213 | Phone: 301 996 8406 | Email: colleen.l.thompson@gmail.com

SKILLS

Curriculum Building Proficient in LPS Desktop, Lender Live, iVAULT, Fastrieve, MSP, Sales Force, File Maker Pro

Proficient in Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher, Pages, Aperture, Photoshop, Basic knowledge of Avid and Final Cut Pro

EXPERIENCE

The Leadership Program

Lead Trainer (Part-Time)

New York, NY

October 2012 - Present

- Provides customized, extended learning experiences in public schools which apply STEM principles
- Designs curriculum in media literacy, video production, and creative writing meeting Common Core State Standards
- Coordinates project logistics to ensure programs run smoothly which includes supervising trainers, liaising with school administrators, ensuring fulfillment of license agreements, and securing recruitment goals

J.P. Morgan Chase

Research Analyst (Contract)

Brooklyn, NY 2011 - May 2012

- Investigated client grievances regarding foreclosure and modification practices for regulatory compliance reviews
- Tracked trends in underwriter research, assisted with conflict resolution, documentation, and with editing reports

The Brooklyn Young Mothers' Collective

Community Organizer

Brooklyn, NY 2007 - 2009

- Developed a social justice program that increased civic engagement within an organization of over 40 members
- Wrote curriculum used in trainings throughout the city, including trainings for the New York State Office of Children and Family Services Staten Island Residence and New York City Department of Education LYFE programs
- Trained young mothers to successfully advocate for revisions in the Chancellor's Regulations for pregnant & parenting students creating an impact felt citywide
- · Conducted outreach, lectures, and presentations for government agencies, community-based organizations, faithbased groups, schools, and conventions including the 23rd Annual Civil Liberties and Public Policy Conference
- · Planned and fundraised for events including minor grant writing as well as securing sponsorship from community businesses and corporate giving programs in the forms of resources, money, and volunteers

The Audre Lorde Project

Project Assistant (Freelance)

Brooklyn, NY 2006 - 2009

- Organized a 70-person summit to address police violence and hate crimes against members of the LGBT community
- Managed volunteers with tasks such as creating a public forum of more than 30 people on neighborhood safety
- Facilitated workshops on community alternative methods both locally and nationally which includes teaching at Critical Resistance 10 in Oakland, CA
- Co-developed a Safe Party Initiative that displayed community-based approaches to violence prevention, intervention, and conflict resolution

Center for Third World Organizing

Brooklyn, NY/New Orleans, LA 2007 - 2009

Program Facilitator (Freelance)

- Assisted New Orleans communities with police and prison reform efforts after Hurricane Katrina through conducting post-release interviews, home visits, door knocking, and event planning
- Facilitated quarterly Community Action Trainings including financial literacy and grassroots fundraising lessons for new recruits to the Movement Action Apprenticeship Program in New York City

EDUCATION

Suffolk University

M.A.: Women's Health Concentration: Health Education, Access & Policy

New York University

B.A.: Sociology, Gender & Sexuality Studies

Boston, MA, 2011

New York, NY, 2007 Minor: Africana Studies

References

Tom Armstrong
The Leadership Program
598 Broadway, 5th Floor
New York, NY 10012
212.625.8001
tarmstrong@theleadershipprogram.com

Benita MillerDeputy Commissioner of Family Permanency Services Administration of Children's Services
150 William Street, 18th Floor
New York, NY 10038
212.341.0981
Benita.miller@dfa.state.ny.us

Ejeris DixonDeputy Director of Community Organizing and Public Advocacy
The Anti-Violence Project
240 W. 35th Street, Suite 200
New York, NY 10001
212.714.1184 x 18
Edixon@avp.org